{
  "category": "Oceanography",
  "difficulty": "easy",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What is the largest ocean on Earth?",
      "options": [
        "Atlantic Ocean",
        "Indian Ocean",
        "Pacific Ocean",
        "Arctic Ocean"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Pacific Ocean",
      "id": "B5087338-9FE7-4D56-88D7-3A6DD84C208F"
    },
    {
      "question": "What term is used to describe the study of the physical and biological aspects of the ocean?",
      "options": [
        "Astronomy",
        "Geology",
        "Meteorology",
        "Oceanography"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Oceanography",
      "id": "F53CC321-9B72-41D3-846E-EC7FA7099C8E"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for the top layer of the ocean surface, where sunlight penetrates sufficiently for photosynthesis to occur?",
      "options": [
        "Epipelagic Zone",
        "Bathypelagic Zone",
        "Mesopelagic Zone",
        "Abyssopelagic Zone"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Epipelagic Zone",
      "id": "A72FCE1E-372D-4A6D-BF91-2B9A242902D0"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the deepest point in the world's oceans?",
      "options": [
        "Mariana Trench",
        "Puerto Rico Trench",
        "Java Trench",
        "Kurilâ€“Kamchatka Trench"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Mariana Trench",
      "id": "583D00F5-3448-420D-93ED-331BCCB3F1C6"
    },
    {
      "question": "What term describes the rising of deep, nutrient-rich water to the surface?",
      "options": [
        "Downwelling",
        "Upwelling",
        "Transpiration",
        "Evaporation"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Upwelling",
      "id": "8E0E3335-519E-4869-BAA0-66CB5F335D70"
    },
    {
      "question": "What term is used to describe a large body of salt water partially enclosed by land?",
      "options": [
        "River",
        "Lake",
        "Sea",
        "Lagoon"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Sea",
      "id": "A49F32A0-F586-465C-9B6B-0AAC1CAA79FF"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the major salt found in the ocean?",
      "options": [
        "Sodium Chloride",
        "Potassium Chloride",
        "Calcium Carbonate",
        "Magnesium Sulphate"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Sodium Chloride",
      "id": "79713DEE-6C62-46BC-8D12-C7D9F9D47DFF"
    },
    {
      "question": "What term is used to describe the regular rise and fall of the sea level, usually caused by the gravitational pull of the Moon and Sun?",
      "options": [
        "Current",
        "Wave",
        "Tide",
        "Ripple"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Tide",
      "id": "85A7B93B-049A-43C8-82DD-C22E383286EA"
    },
    {
      "question": "What term is used to describe a large, flat area of the sea floor?",
      "options": [
        "Seamount",
        "Trench",
        "Abyssal Plain",
        "Continental Slope"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Abyssal Plain",
      "id": "0BE436A7-8590-41DD-BA4E-C52540303655"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name for a steep descent of the sea floor from the continental shelf to the abyssal zone?",
      "options": [
        "Continental Rise",
        "Continental Drift",
        "Continental Slope",
        "Continental Divide"
      ],
      "correct_answer": "Continental Slope",
      "id": "9A037519-7FEA-4996-BA8F-C844166E151E"
    }
  ]
}
